<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LibraryVPN</title>
    <link>https://libraryvpn.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LibraryVPN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:44:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://libraryvpn.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:44:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/about/</guid>
      <description>People are increasingly concerned by attacks on their online security and privacy. Those who cannot afford broadband access in their home have to rely on free public wifi hotspots where security can be minimal and there are no built in security or privacy protection. Even those who can afford their own internet service have reason to worry about applications abusing their access to gather information and sell it for profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Is This the Library&#39;s Role?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/why-is-this-the-librarys-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 13:59:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/why-is-this-the-librarys-role/</guid>
      <description>Library VPN brings together two ideas that are both widely accepted in modern library practice. 1. Libraries should work to protect patron privacy 2. Libraries host online services for their patrons
Libraries have long worked to protect patron privacy. Librarian sometimes refer to this as the &amp;ldquo;Freedom to Read&amp;rdquo;, but this extends far beyond physical books. We care about people being able to exercise their intellectual freedom when accessing information, regardless of the form that information takes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can We Run LibraryVPN if We Do Not Have IT Staff?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/can-we-run-libraryvpn-if-we-do-not-have-it-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/can-we-run-libraryvpn-if-we-do-not-have-it-staff/</guid>
      <description>We would not recommend hosting LibraryVPN without dedicated IT staff. However we are hoping to have a hosted version available in the future so that all libraries can take advantage of their software to protect their patron&amp;rsquo;s privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Potential Risks to running LibraryVPN?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/what-are-potential-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 16:28:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/what-are-potential-risks/</guid>
      <description>If you are self-hosting LibraryVPN you should be aware that anything a patron does while connected to the VPN will appear to come from your IP address. This is already the case when patrons use a libraries public internet or WIFI so this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big of a change for libraries. Like when patrons use the public wifi available within the library, they may decide to do bad things while using the library&amp;rsquo;s VPN connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is behind LibraryVPN?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/who-is-behind-libraryvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 15:06:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/who-is-behind-libraryvpn/</guid>
      <description>LibraryVPN is an IMLS funded project. It is being developed by a partnership of libraries including the Lebanon Public Libraries, the Westchester Library System, and the Cherry hill Public Library working with LEAP. This software is free and opensource, so anyone who wishes to can install it and run it free of charge. We are currently investigated the possibility of a hosted version of this software for libraries that wish to use it, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to host it for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>