<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LibraryVPN</title>
    <link>https://libraryvpn.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LibraryVPN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:44:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://libraryvpn.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:44:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Library VPN LibraryVPN is a free and open source software project that allows libraries to host a Virtual Private Network (VPN) for their patrons.
Patrons will download an easy to use client for their Windows, Mac, or Linux computer. They will then connect using their library card to have access to a free, high quality, and secure VPN from a provider that they know that they can trust, their local public library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Everyone on the Library Network Use the VPN?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/will-everyone-on-the-library-network-use-the-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:40:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/will-everyone-on-the-library-network-use-the-vpn/</guid>
      <description>No, your existing library network will not be affected. Only people who choose to connect through the VPN client will use the VPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can We Run LibraryVPN if We Do Not Have IT Staff?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/can-we-run-libraryvpn-if-we-do-not-have-it-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:04:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/can-we-run-libraryvpn-if-we-do-not-have-it-staff/</guid>
      <description>We would not recommend hosting LibraryVPN without dedicated IT staff. However we are hoping to have a hosted version available in the future so that all libraries can take advantage of their software to protect their patron&amp;rsquo;s privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Potential Risks to running LibraryVPN?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/what-are-potential-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 16:28:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/what-are-potential-risks/</guid>
      <description>If you are self-hosting LibraryVPN you should be aware that anything a patron does while connected to the VPN will appear to come from your IP address. This is already the case when patrons use a libraries public internet or WIFI so this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big of a change for libraries. Like when patrons use the public wifi available within the library, they may decide to do bad things while using the library&amp;rsquo;s VPN connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is behind LibraryVPN?</title>
      <link>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/who-is-behind-libraryvpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 15:06:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libraryvpn.org/faq/who-is-behind-libraryvpn/</guid>
      <description>LibraryVPN is an IMLS funded project. It is being developed by a partnership of libraries including the Lebanon Public Libraries, the Westchester Library System, and the Cherry hill Public Library working with LEAP. This software is free and opensource, so anyone who wishes to can install it and run it free of charge. We are currently investigated the possibility of a hosted version of this software for libraries that wish to use it, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to host it for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>